Jimmy Baynes Collection (Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum Collection) ARC.0161
Library and Archives
- Series II: Artists, 1953-1973, 1983, undated
  - Wilson, Ralph, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Black-and-white 8" x 10" photograph of Ralph Wilson on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
    During the mid- to late-1950s, Ralph Wilson and his orchestra played regularly at John Ballard’s Chatterbox (5123 Woodland Avenue). They were the house band for special guests like Brook Benton, Billie Holiday, Arthur Prysock, Della Reese, Jimmy Rushing, Titus Turner and T-Bone Walker. Their previous gig was at the Rose Room of the Majestic Hotel (East 55th Street), which they left mid-1952 for Duke Jenkins and his orchestra to take over.
  - Wilson, Teddy, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Young, Stella "Caldonia", undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    The Stella “Caldonia” Young Revue was essentially a touring vaudevillian show with male and female vocalists, tap dancers, comedians, and Young herself, an exotic shake dancer and contortionist, as master of ceremonies. Young not only dance professionally but took time to teach dance to Cleveland locals like George Hendricks, Vanilla Thomas, and young jazz legend Jimmy Scott. Young also managed the Five Hepsters, who became the Hepsters in 1955. Comedian Charlie Eckstein is pictured on the far left.
- Series III: Record Distributors, 1963, undated
  Series III: Record Distibutors, 1963, undated, includes a copy of the "Mid-Atlantic Record Review" and a flyer from Seaway Distributing Co. The "Mid-Atlantic Record Review" was prepared each week by Mimeo Unlimited, located at 330 Film Building, Cleveland, Ohio. It was a complete listing of the latest releases from distributors King, Cosnat, Mangold, Free State, and Marnel. Seaway Distributing Co. was located at 3142 Prospect Ave, Cleveland, Ohio. The flyer advertises the company's singles showing action, hits, polka singles, new Riverside albums, other Riverside LPs, new battle album, other battle LPs, and new Washington albums.
  - "Mid-Atlantic Record Review", 1963 September 23 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Seaway Distributing Co., undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Radio Stations, 1961-1966
  Series IV: Radio Stations, 1961-1966, includes an unidentified disc jockey photograph and "Radio 100 Sound Surveys" from KYW; several WHK channel 14 Tunedex charts; a WIXY-60 music survey; and a program for a "city wide salute" to Mary C. Holt of WJMO.
  - KYW, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Unidentified disc jockey photograph and "Radio 100 Sound Surveys."
  - WHK Channel 14 Tunedex charts, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - WIXY, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - WJMO program for "city wide salute" to Mary C. Holt, 1962 August 12 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series V: Venues, 1962-1971, undated
  Series V: Venues spans the years 1962 to 1971 and includes some undated materials. The series contains promotional materials and black-and-white exterior photographs and negatives for a few local Cleveland nightclubs and other music venues, including the Ankara, Cabin Club, Carlton House, Cleveland Arena, Club Manhattan, Club Trinidad, Cotton Club, Gus's Show Bar Lounge, Lancer, Leo's Casino, Mirror Show Bar, and the Wheel Lounge. In addition to the photographic materials, there is a promotional photograph mat, a ticket, an invitation, match books, and a menu. The files are arranged alphabetically by venue name. Additional information on the particular venues has been included in the finding aid at the file-level where available.
  - Abbott's BBQ, undated (Box 2, Folder 22a)
  - Ankara, 1966 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 22b)
    "Jazz soriee" ticket. The Ankara was on Route 51. The concert was presented by the "Bafa Girls": Donna Battle, Blondeva Wharton, and Ann Turner and included a performance by Jimmy McGriff's Combo.
  - Cabin Club, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Two (2) matchbooks. The Cabin Club was located at 10616 Euclid Ave, Cleveland, Ohio.
  - Carlton House, 1971 July 3 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Cabaret party invitation (business card size). The Carlton House was located at 1954 E 79th St. The party included a performance by the Soul Breeds.
  - Cleveland Arena, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    The Arena was located at 3717 Euclid, built in 1937. It was the site in March 1952 of radio deejay Alan Freed’s Moondog Coronation Ball. These photographs all appear to be from the Biggest Rock ‘n Roll Show of ’56, which featured artists LaVern Baker, the Colts, Bo Diddley, the Drifters, the Flamingos, Bill Haley and the Comets, Clyde McPhatter, the Platters, the Teen Queens, Frankie Lymon and the Teenagers, Joe Turner, and Red Prysock and his “Rock ‘n Roll” Orchestra. With the opening of Richfield Coliseum in 1974, the Arena ceased to host major events and was demolished in early 1977.
    Black-and-white photograph of the exterior on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
  - Club Manhattan, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Club Trinidad, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Menu. "House of Jazz" Club Trinidad was located at 10607 Superior Ave, Cleveland, Ohio.
  - Cotton Club, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Located at 2230 E 4th St, Cleveland, Ohio. Opened in 1954. By early 1955, club owner Sam Firsten began presenting national jazz acts, usually for a week at a time, including Gene Ammons, Art Blakey and His Jazz Messengers, Herbie Mann, Charlie Mingus, Bud Powell, and the very popular J. J. Johnson and Kai Winding. In 1957, club owner Sam Firsten renamed it the Moden Jazz Room.
  - Gus's Show Bar Lounge, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Includes Rea & Bea.
  - Lancer, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Leo's Casino, 1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    The original Leo’s Casino was a bar opened in 1952 by Leo Frank at Central Avenue and East 48th Street. Frank expanded his bar into a jazz room and booked greats such as Dizzy Gillespie, Lou Rawls, and John Coltrane. After the fire, it moved to Carnegie Avenue. In September 1963, Frank was joined by partner Jules Berger, and they opened a new, bigger nightclub in the Quad Hall Hotel at 7500 Euclid Avenue. The new Leo’s Casino seated about 700 people and became the top club for soul and R&B acts, featuring Motown and touring national acts, as well as jazz artists. By the late 1960s, however, the costs of booking top name entertainers had skyrocketed, and the club closed in 1972. In 1999, the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame designated the Euclid Avenue site of the club a historic landmark.
  - Mirror Show Bar, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Jimmy Baynes photograph presentation mat. The Mirror Show Bar was located at 12376 Superior Ave, Cleveland, Ohio. The Mirror Show was a cocktail lounge with nightly entertainment.
  - Wheel Lounge, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Jimmy Baynes photograph presentation mat. The Wheel Lounge was located at 4461 Lee Rd, Cleveland, Ohio. The Lounge specialized in southern barbeque, shoulder, steaks, and chickens. It catered clubs, banquets, and all social events. The proprieter was known simply as "Lu."
- Series VI: Unidentified Individuals, 1955-1965, undated
  Series VI: Unidentifed Individuals spans the years 1955 to 1965 and includes undated materials. The series consists of black-and-white and color photographs and negatives. The photographic materials were arranged into two files: female performers and male performers, with an additional file of individuals that could not be identified by name or as performers. Identifiable venues include the Band Box, Club Trinidad, and the Music Box. Dated photographs can be found at the front of the file in chronological order; undated photos at the back. Please note that many of the dates reflect the date the film was processed, not necessarily the date of the performance.
  - Female Performers, 1955, 1960, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Male Performers, 1955-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Other/Unknown, 1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Series VII: Unidentified Groups, 1959, undated
  The materials in Series VII: Unidentified Groups, 1959, undated, have been arranged into 2 files: instrumental groups and vocal groups, with a third file for groups that could not be identified by name or as a performing group. Most performances area assumed to be from Cleveland-area shows. Identifiable venues include Abbotts, the Masonic Temple, and the Music Box. The series consists of black-and-white and color photographs and negatives. Dated photographs can be found at the front of the photograph in chronological order; undated photos at the back. Please note that many of the dates reflect the date the film was processed, not necessarily the date of the performance.
  - Instrumental, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Vocal, 1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Other/Unknown, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Series VIII: Miscellaneous, 1960
  Series VIII: Miscellaneous, 1960, contains a single issue of the pocket magazine OPAL, from Pride Publications (Cleveland, Ohio). The staff of OPAL included Valena M. Williams, executive editor; John Bentley, art director; and Nathaniel Hubbard, circulation manager. Volume 1, issue 5 includes work by photographers James Gayle, Anderson Marlow, and Harvey Bowie; columnists Bill Clark, Harrison Dillard, Edward Jones, William Matlock, and Mary Zachary; and artwork by cartoonist Ted Walker. It is possible one of the photographs in the magazine could be by Baynes, but none are cited as such. The publication contains information from members of the local community on birthday celebrations and other upcoming events, contest winners, and fashion, as well as longer articles on jazz, the importance of education and peaceful protests, the influence of disc jockeys and popular music on teens, WJMO's middle school student disc jockeys, singer Nancy Wilson, and Isabelle Cooley, co-star of the feature film I Passed for White.
  - Cleveland Opal, Volume 1, Issue 5, 1960 May 18 (Box 2, Folder 40)